Bess Furman Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, circa 1919-1960 (Box 36-63)
  - White House
    - General, (5 folders); (19 folders); (7 folders) (Box 59, Box 60)
    - Children in
    - Egg rolling
    - Functions
    - Inventories
    - Kitchens
    - Renovation, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 61)
    - Visiting royalty
    - Women in
  - White House conferences
    - Aging
    - Children and Youth, (2 folders)
    - Health, (2 folders)
  - Wilder, Thornton
  - Willkie, Wendell L., (2 folders) (Box 62)
  - Wilson, Woodrow
  - Woman suffrage
  - Women
  - Women in CIO-PAC
  - Women in Congress
  - Women in politics
    - Democrats
    - Republicans
  - Women in public life, (7 folders)
  - Women in the public service (Box 63)
  - Women's Bureau
  - Women's Division, A.F. of L., League for Political Education
  - Women's Division, Democratic National Committee
  - Women's National Democratic Club
  - Women's National Press Club, (4 folders)
  - Women's organizations
  - Work Projects Administration
- Speeches and Writings File, circa 1919-1960 (Box 64-117)
  Printed articles, drafts of articles and books, galley proofs, research material, notebooks, and related correspondence.
  Arranged alphabetically by title, topic, or type of writing.
  - Agriculture Department (Box 64)
  - American Association of University Women, (2 folders)
  - "Among My Memorabilia" (speech)
  - Articles
    - Ideas
    - Printed
      - circa 1919-1929, (4 folders)
      - 1925, (1 folder) (Box 65)
      - 1926, (2 folders)
      - 1927, (1 folder) (Box 66)
      - 1928-1929, (2 folders)
      - 1930s See Containers 144-152, Scrapbooks
      - 1943-1945, (4 folders)
      - 1946-1951, (13 folders) (Box 67)
      - 1952-1954, (9 folders) (Box 68)
      - 1955-1957, (12 folders) (Box 69)
      - 1958-1959, (8 folders) (Box 70)
      - 1960, (2 folders) (Box 71)
      - Undated See also Containers 144-153, Scrapbooks
    - Miscellaneous, (9 folders); (13 folders) (Box 72)
  - "As Billings Ordered–Public Health" (speech) (Box 73)
  - "At Home–That's Hyde Park–with the Roosevelts"
  - "Bigger Than a By-Line"
  - "Brookings as Landlord"
  - Bureau of Home Economics
  - "Cabinet Daughter"
  - "The Capitol and How It Grew"
  - Caraway, Hattie
  - "The Career Comprehensive"
  - "The Child Grows Up"
  - Child welfare
  - "Children as Weapons of War"
  - Children's Bureau, Department of Labor (articles)
  - "The Children's Bureau Aim–A Better Chance for Every Child"
  - "CMC Expert Tells of Capture by Germans"
  - The Democratic Digest (articles by Lucile N. Furman and Bess Furman)
  - Democratic National Committee (writings for)
  - "A Dome, a Dream and a Grand Cascade"
  - "Don't Cry in a Crisis"
  - "A Few Notes on 151 White House Years"
  - "Full House", (8 folders) (Box 74)
  - General Federation (speech to)
  - Hoover, Herbert
  - "I Know 'Em From the Skin Out"
  - "It's Your Washington"
  - "John Tyler's Widow", (3 folders)
  - "Ladies of the White House", (3 folders) (Box 75)
  - "Mary Anderson Goes Marching On"
  - National League of Women Voters
  - National Maternal and Child Health Council
  - "A New Christmas Custom at Old St. John's"
  - Notebooks (including typed transcripts)
    - 1930-1935, (2 folders)
    - 1934-1935, (4 folders) (Box 76)
    - 1935-1936, (5 folders) (Box 77)
    - 1936-1942, (5 folders) (Box 78)
    - 1943-1951, (3 folders) (Box 79)
    - 1953-1959, (4 vols.) (Box 80)
    - 1960 (Box 81)
    - Undated, (3 folders); (5 folders); (4 folders); (17 vols. and 1 folder) (Box 82, Box 83, Box 84, Box 85, Box 86, Box 87)
  - "Nutrition for the Nations" (Box 88)
  - Office of War Information, (2 folders)
  - "One Way Ticket to Washington"
  - "One Women Scientist's Answer to Cancer", (2 folders)
  - "Our Washington"
  - "A Peanut Politician" (Calvin Coolidge article)
  - "The People's White House"
  - Poems
  - A Profile of the United States Public Health Service, correspondence, drafts, and related material, (4 folders); (5 folders); (2 folders) (Box 89, Box 90, Box 91, Box 92)
  - Progress in Prothetics, correspondence, galley, and related material, (2 folders)
  - "Prolonging Useful Life"
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor (articles)
  - "Shall We Join the Gentlemen" (speech)
  - "So You're Going to Write a Book"
  - "The Twin Type of Life"
  - "There's a Truer Word Than Widow"
  - "Washington By-Line" (speech)
  - Washington By-Line (Box 93)
    - Drafts, outline, galley proofs, notes, research material, correspondence, reviews, publicity, and related material, (16 folders); (4 folders); (8 folders); (6 folders); (9 folders); (3 folders); (12 folders); (20 folders); (10 folders) (Box 94, Box 95, Box 96, Box 97, Box 98, Box 99, Box 100, Box 101, Box 102, Box 103, Box 104, Box 105, Box 106)
  - "We Share Our Washington" (unpublished book idea), correspondence, outline
  - "Welcome to Our Changed Capital City"
  - "When the Mails Go Through Again"
  - White House Conference on Children
  - White House Profile, draft, outline, research materials, correspondence and related material, (1 folder); (3 folders); (12 folders); (10 folders); (11 folders); (15 folders); (4 folders); (5 folders) (Box 107, Box 108, Box 109, Box 110, Box 111, Box 112, Box 113, Box 114, Box 115, Box 116, Box 117)
  - "Woman Between Two Worlds"
  - "Women Have Learned to Count in Public Life"
- Miscellany, 1903-1966 (Box 118-155)
  Address books, addresses, appointment books, calendars, clippings, financial papers, greeting cards, household papers, invitations, announcements, calling cards, membership cards, memorabilia, notes, scrapbooks, writings by others, and miscellaneous other items.
  Arranged by type of material.
  - Address books, (4 vols.) (Box 118)
  - Addresses
  - Appointment books
    - 1955
    - 1958-1959, (2 folders)
    - 1961
  - Calendars
    - 1935-1936, (2 folders)
    - 1938-1941, (4 folders)
    - 1943-1944, (2 folders) (Box 119)
    - 1946
    - 1948
    - 1949-1952, (4 folders) (Box 120)
    - 1953-1954, (2 folders); (2 vols.) (Box 121)
    - 1955 (Box 122)
    - 1956, (2 vols.)
    - 1958
    - 1959-1961, (3 folders) (Box 123)
    - 1963-1964, (2 folders)
    - 1965-1966, (2 folders) (Box 124)
  - Clippings
    - Armstrong, Robert B., Sr.
    - Furman, Bess, and family, (2 folders)
    - Johnson, Lady Bird (Box 125)
    - Johnson, Lyndon B., and family
    - Kennedy, Jacqueline
    - Religion
    - General, (1 folder); (5 folders) (Box 126, Box 127)
  - Financial papers (Box 128)
    - Account books, 1923-1946, (3 vols.)
    - Accounts, (3 folders)
    - Bills and receipts (Box 129)
      - 1949-1955, (2 folders)
      - 1956-1959, (5 folders) (Box 130)
      - 1960-1963, (3 folders) (Box 131)
      - 1964-1966, (2 folders) (Box 132)
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 133)
    - Canceled checks, (2 folders)
    - Deed, 1927 (Box 134)
    - Insurance
    - Miscellany
    - Montserrat property
    - Taxes
      - 1939-1955, (4 folders)
      - 1956-1960, (6 folders) (Box 135)
      - 1961-1966, (6 folders) (Box 136)
    - Warrantees
  - General, (4 folders) (Box 137)
  - Greeting cards, (1 folder); (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 138, Box 139)
  - Household papers
  - Houses
  - Invitations, announcements, and calling cards, (1 folder); (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 140, Box 141)
  - Lecture tour (Box 142)
  - Membership cards
  - Memorabilia
  - News release sources
  - News teletype reports
  - Notes, (2 folders); (6 folders); (4 folders) (Box 143, Box 144)
  - Press releases
  - Scrapbooks
    - Armstrong, Robert Burns (1903-1955), clippings of his writings, 1944
    - Comet's Camp-Fire Count book
    - Furman, Bess, and family (Box 145)
      - Clippings of letters from Bess Furman published in newspapers and other articles, 1929-1940 (4 vols. and some loose clippings)
      - Newspaper work of the years 1918-1919 by Bess Furman (Box 146)
      - Mattie Furman's scrapbook of clippings about Bess Furman and clippings of her articles; also letters from and about Bess Furman, circa 1931-1934
      - Clippings by and about Bess Furman; also correspondence with Associated Press (includes newspaper columns written under pseudonym "Bobbie O'Dare")
      - Hazel Furman's scrapbook including clippings of articles by herself and Bess Furman
      - Scrapbook pages kept for Bess Furman by her cousin Dale See Oversize
      - Children's scrapbook See Oversize
      - Clippings including a number of Bobbie O'Dare articles See Oversize
      - Scrapbook on electric trains by Robert Armstrong See Oversize
      - Book of clippings mostly on Bess Furman and Matrix Table, 1955 See Oversize
      - Robbie Armstrong scrapbook See Oversize
      - Clippings of articles by Bess Furman for New York Times See Oversize, (2 vols.)
    - Mallon, Winifred, scrapbooks of articles written for the New York Times; includes some correspondence (Box 147)
      - 1903-1920
      - 1921-1923
      - 1925-1928 (Box 148)
      - 1929-1930
      - 1930 (Box 149)
      - 1931-1932
      - 1932-1933, (2 folders) (Box 150)
      - 1934-1935, (2 folders) (Box 151)
      - 1937 (Box 152)
      - 1939
      - 1942 (Box 153)
      - 1943-1944
      - 1945 See Oversize
  - Writings by others (Box 154)
    - "Daily Drift"
    - Dickson, Cecil B.
      - "Roosevelt's Inner Circle"
      - Untitled manuscript, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 155)
    - "Down with Dailies or Why All Omaha Newspaper Plants Should Be Blown to Smithereens"
    - Enochs, Elisabeth Shirley, "Mount Air"
    - Gregg, Isaac. "Playing Santa Claus to Civilized World"
    - Newhill, E. B., "The Modern Airplane of Today and Tomorrow"
    - Rogers, Edith Nourse, "The Good Old New England Way Into the Future"
    - Sherman, Fanny Jessop, Admiral Wags
    - Stastny, Olga, "A Look Ahead"
    - "Therefore"
    - Untitled excerpt from the Writers Digest
- Oversize (Box OV 1-OV 4)
  Scrapbooks and clippings.
  Arranged and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Family (Box OV 1)
    - Armstrong, Robert Burns
      - Miscellany
        - Certificate (Container 9)
  - Miscellany (Box OV 2)
    - Scrapbooks
      - Furman, Bess, and family
        - Scrapbook pages kept for Bess Furman by her cousin Dale (Container 146)
        - Children's scrapbook (Container 146)
        - Clippings including a number of Bobbie O'Dare articles (Container 146)
        - Scrapbook on electric trains by Robert Armstrong (Container 146) (Box OV 3)
        - Book of clippings mostly on Bess Furman and Matrix Table, 1955 (Container 146)
        - Robbie Armstrong scrapbook (Container 146)
      - Mallon, Winifred, scrapbooks of articles written for the New York Times; includes some correspondence, 1945 (Container 153)
      - Clippings of articles by Bess Furman for New York Times (Container 146), (2 vols.) (Box OV 4)